A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H FA317
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Clubs
  - Clubs - Tarrytown Boat Club, 1938-1961 (Box 23, Folder 164)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd inactive members. 1959, Laurance S. Rockefeller invested in new marina. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    90T
  - Clubs - Thirteen West 54th Street Club, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 165)
    Organized by Rockefeller brothers and a few friends. Rules of club. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    90T1
  - Clubs - Union League Club, 1917-1940 (Box 23, Folder 166)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. a member; contributions toward war work during World War 1. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    90U1
  - Clubs - University Club of New York, 1916-1959 (Box 23, Folder 167)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. became life member, 1916; letters of endorsement for new members. Club activities; gifts and loans to club. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    90U2
  - Clubs - University Club of New York, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 0167A)
  - Clubs - University Club of New York - David Rockefeller Membership, 1940-1961 (Box 23, Folder 168)
    David Rockefeller membership proposed by Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Clubs - University Club of New York - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1929-1961 (Box 23, Folder 169)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd a member; letters seconding candidates. 1959 meeting for Lincoln Center, with John D. Rockefeller 3rd presiding.
  - Clubs - University Club of New York - Laurance S. Rockefeller Membership, 1936-1961 (Box 24, Folder 170)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller membership, letters seconding candidates.
  - Clubs - University Club of New York - Laurance S. Rockefeller Membership, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 0170A)
  - Clubs - University Club of Province, 1902-1939 (Box 24, Folder 171)
    90U3
  - Clubs - Union Club, 1939-1959 (Box 24, Folder 172)
    90U4
  - Clubs - Warwick Country Club, 1930-1939 (Box 24, Folder 173)
    90W
  - Clubs - Women's City Club of New York, 1935-1961 (Box 24, Folder 174)
    Contributions by Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. John D. Rockefeller 3rd spoke to Club regarding Lincoln Center in 1956. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    90W1
  - Clubs - Women's City Club of New York, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 0174A)
  - Clubs - Whitehall Club, 1910-1957 (Box 24, Folder 175)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. became member, 1910, in order to use gym. Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Raymond B. Fosdick and Dr. Buttrick also members. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. proposed Everett Colby; made loan and gifts to gym instructor, Otto Tanzer. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution for squash court; resignation in 1933. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined honorary membership. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Walter Kidde.
  - Clubs - Washington Educational Touring Club, 1952-1957 (Box 24, Folder 176)
    Negro club awarded plaque to John D. Rockefeller, Sr. - John D. Rockefeller 3rd accepted. John D. Rockefeller 3rd interest. Correspondents include Arthur Sweetzer, George Wallace, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    90W2
- Dancing
  - Dancing - Dancing Class, 1914-1952 (Box 24, Folder 177)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s selections of music for dinners in his home. Participation in Leap Year dances. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    14
- Detectives
  - Detective Agencies - Special Investigations, 1915-1946 (Box 24, Folder 178)
    Colorado detective on Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I) strike issue; requests for position as private detective. Impersonation of John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    55
  - Detective Agencies - Regarding Miss Bruton, 1937-1940 (Box 24, Folder 179)
- Doctors
  - Doctors - Miscellaneous Memos, 1940-1964; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 180)
    Doctors' bills for care of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller; medical expenses at birth of Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller. Unwillingness of some doctors to name a specific fee for services rendered. Doctors' proposals of special projects. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. appreciation for services rendered. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    231
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted - Confidential material.
  - Doctors - Miscellaneous Memos, 1908-1939; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 181)
  - Doctors - Dr. Max Gerson, 1941-1946 (Box 25, Folder 182)
    Proposed cure for tuberculosis; no Rockefeller support.
  - Doctors - Dr. John H. Kellogg, 1938-1950 (Box 25, Folder 183)
    Wrote to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. about diet and care.
  - Doctors - Dr. Adelbert Ames, Jr., 1928-1931; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 184)
    Researcher at Dartmouth Medical School, son of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s friend, Gen. Adelbert Ames, was consulted by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. regarding John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s eye troubles and headaches. Failure of different prescriptions for glasses to reduce headaches; graphs of headache recurrence; detailed reports of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s eyes, past and present. Correspondence with Drs. Lancaster, Knapp and Wilmer. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s support of Ames' work; Ames' discouragement regarding spreading of his discoveries. Examinations of Laurance S. Rockefeller and Winthrop Rockefeller. Correspondents include Dr. Adelbert Ames, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. Lancaster, Dr. Gordon H. Gliddon.
    231Am1
  - Doctors - Dr. Adelbert Ames, Jr., 1932-1945; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 185)
  - Doctors - Dr. H. T. Chickering, 1925-1943 (Box 26, Folder 186)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. sent friends and employees to Chickering for medical advice. Letter from World War I veteran who was cured of foot infection by Carrel-Dekin solution. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. frequently paid for doctor's services to others. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    231C3
  - Doctors - Dr. William B. Coley, 1910-1941 (Box 26, Folder 187)
    A specialist on cancer, friend of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s marriage gift to Coley's son; gift to Dr. Coley. Dr. Coley's death; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gifts to widow. Correspondence with Coley's daughter. Correspondents include Mrs. W. B. Nants, Dr. William Coley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    231C71
  - Doctors - Dr. John Dane, 1932-1939 (Box 26, Folder 188)
    Treated John D. Rockefeller, Jr. headaches and shoulder trouble with osteopathy. Visits to Dane home; personal friendship; Dr. Dane's death. Search for a new osteopath. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. and Mrs. John Dane.
    231D1
  - Doctors - Dr. Theodore Dunham, 1921-1952 (Box 26, Folder 189)
    Rockefeller family physician and close personal friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Gifts to him of money and car. Deaths of Dr. and Mrs. Dunham. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Theodore Dunham.
    231D8
  - Doctors - Dr. Ernest Krug, 1905-1948 (Box 26, Folder 190)
    Eye, ear, nose and throat man - primarily John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s doctor. John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gift to him; Krug projects regarding medical education. Dr. Krug's death. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Dr. R. Pearce, Dr. Krug.
    231K9
  - Doctors - Dr. Robert H. Morris, 1934-1946 (Box 26, Folder 191)
    Orthopedist, treated John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller for knee and foot trouble, also a stiff arm. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    231M7
  - Doctors - Dr. John H. Richards, 1931-1960 (Box 26, Folder 192)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s general physician - had attended John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Bible Class, was John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s personal friend. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s annual gifts to Richards, financing of his trip to Williamsburg, buying of Richards' house and letting Richards use it free. Helped him set up trust for himself and children. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dr. J. Richards, Thomas M. Debevoise, Robert W. Gumbel.
    231R4
  - Doctors - Dr. William D. Tracy, 1922-1957 (Box 26, Folder 193)
    Dentist, treated John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s family. Confusion over removal of wrong tooth for Winthrop Rockefeller. Dr. Tracy's death; switch to Dr. Robertson. Gifts to Dr. Robertson and his staff. Correspondents include Dr. Tracy, Dr. Robertson, Miss Van Houten, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    231T7
- Donations
  - Donations - Congressional Institutions - Frank Hanser (John D. Rockefeller, Sr.), 1895-1917 (Box 26, Folder 194)
    Summary of gifts to congregational institutions during "tainted money" scandal. Loan for hospitalization, not repaid.
    2
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - General, 1918-1921; Folder 1 of 5 (Box 27, Folder 195)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to individuals and some institutions. Record of "out of pocket" small gifts. Lists of small gifts for various years. Many "nest egg" gifts. Gifts in 1938 by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. estate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - General, 1922-1928; Folder 2 of 5 (Box 27, Folder 0195A)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - General, 1929-1933; Folder 3 of 5 (Box 27, Folder 196)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - General, 1934-1937; Folder 4 of 5 (Box 27, Folder 197)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - General, 1934-1937; Folder 5 of 5 (Box 27, Folder 198)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - Mrs. J. A. Burr, 1934-1936 (Box 28, Folder 199)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - Marion M. Calloway, 1933-1937 (Box 28, Folder 200)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - L. Vernon Chase, 1935-1937 (Box 28, Folder 201)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - J. L. Cheney, 1933-1936 (Box 28, Folder 202)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - Mabel H. Duncan, 1933-1936 (Box 28, Folder 203)
  - Donations - John D. Rockefeller Estate, 1925-1938 (Box 28, Folder 204)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - Seville Radcliffe Ellsworth, 1933-1935 (Box 28, Folder 205)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - Elias M. Johnson, 1934-1935 (Box 28, Folder 206)
  - Donations - Mr. Rockefeller, Sr. - Eva Warner, 1932-1936 (Box 28, Folder 207)
  - Donations - John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Lists (Box 28, Folder 208)
    Lists of personal gifts by John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laura Spelman Rockefeller and Miss Spelman. Correspondence destroyed in 1951. Some summary statements of total gifts for some years.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, 1914-1926; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 209)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, 1928-1937; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 210)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1940-1944; Folder 1 of 8 (Box 28, Folder 211)
    Personal gifts to individuals and some small gifts to institutions. Size of gifts increased sharply in later years. Many of the gifts made in time of personal crisis. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1945-1952; Folder 2 of 8 (Box 29, Folder 212)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1952-1955; Folder 3 of 8 (Box 29, Folder 213)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1956; Folder 4 of 8 (Box 29, Folder 214)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1956-1958; Folder 5 of 8 (Box 29, Folder 215)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1959; Folder 6 of 8 (Box 29, Folder 216)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1959-1960; Folder 7 of 8 (Box 30, Folder 217)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans, 1960; Folder 8 of 8 (Box 30, Folder 218)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts
    To friends, relations, employees; list covering all 1917-1960 gifts. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts, 1917-1940 (Box 30, Folder 219)
    - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts, 1917-1937 (Box 30, Folder 220)
    - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts, 1943-1950 (Box 30, Folder 221)
    - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 222)
    - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts, 1952-1955 (Box 31, Folder 223)
    - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts, 1955-1960 (Box 31, Folder 223A)
      Restricted material.
    - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Wedding Gifts, 1956-1960 (Box 31, Folder 224)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Fry, 1945-1959 (Box 31, Folder 225)
    Voice teacher; gifts for vocalist training at Pocantico Hills church.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Fred J. Lovatt, 1912-1947 (Box 31, Folder 226)
    Worked for John D. Rockefeller, Jr., then went into own brokerage business; acute financial difficulties. Regular gifts from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Ella Grant Wilson, 1937-1941 (Box 31, Folder 227)
    Wrote books on Euclid Avenue; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. load for continuing work; her death. Loans never paid off.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - William E. Church, 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 228)
    Financial difficulties of Willard S. Richardson friend; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. loans, paid back.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Alfred J. Robertson, 1908-1956 (Box 31, Folder 229)
    Bible Class friend borrowed from John D. Rockefeller, Jr., repaid loans; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Dr. Anson Phelps Stokes, 1935-1950 (Box 31, Folder 230)
    Trustee of various Rockefeller boards, wrote book on Church and State in the United States. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave him $5,000 towards its publication; highly favorable review of the work.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Margaret Millerman, 1924-1926 (Box 32, Folder 231)
    An "old market lady" in a difficult plight aided by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift via Charles White.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Margaret Applegarth, 1934-1937 (Box 32, Folder 232)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Almeda C. Adams, 1894-1925 (Box 32, Folder 233)
    Blind Cleveland girl aided by John D. Rockefeller. Sr. - a member of music school settlement.
    2Ad1
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Dr. Elroy Avery, 1924-1935 (Box 32, Folder 234)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. sent Florida friend $200 annually.
    2Av
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Helen Beckman, 1902-1940 (Box 32, Folder 236)
    Daughter of Polly Rockefeller, a cousin; small gifts.
    2B3
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Ida R. Bradley, 1897-1947 (Box 32, Folder 237)
    Children of W. A. Rockefeller's brother lived in Phelps, New York. John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s gifts continued after 1935 by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    2B8
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mary A. Brusie, 1902-1953 (Box 32, Folder 238)
    Gifts by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to John D. Rockefeller, Sr. cousin.
    2B88
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Courtland Butler, 1923-1934 (Box 33, Folder 239)
    Minister, golf partner of John D. Rockefeller, Sr., received small gifts.
    2B97
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Theresa Balboni, 1914-1923 (Box 33, Folder 240)
    Pocantico Hills employee received aid for aged mother.
    2B11
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Herman Case, 1923-1934 (Box 33, Folder 241)
    Germantown, New York relative received $30 per month from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    2C
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Kate Cannon, 1914-1923 (Box 33, Folder 242)
    Member of 5th Avenue Baptist Church got small gifts.
    2C11
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - John Deane, 1895-1923 (Box 33, Folder 243)
    Blind New York real estate broker got small gifts.
    2D3
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Anne Donohue, 1911-1937 (Box 33, Folder 244)
    Former servant got small monthly sums from John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
    2D75
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. and Mrs. W. Drummond, 1912-1950 (Box 33, Folder 245)
    Small gifts to members of 5th Avenue Baptist Church.
    2D9
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - W. B. Davidson, 1922-1954 (Box 34, Folder 246)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. small monthly sums to relative.
    2D11
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Julia and Susan Emery, 1916-1953 (Box 34, Folder 247)
    Nursed Rockefeller children, her recollections of them. Received monthly gifts, purchase of home in Massachusetts.
    2Em
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Julia and Susan Emery - Regarding Arrangements for Trust Agreements, 1931-1942 (Box 34, Folder 248)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Miss Annie Etzenperger, 1894-1942 (Box 34, Folder 249)
    Small John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to Cleveland teacher.
    2Et8
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Harry B. Fritz, 1917-1934 (Box 34, Folder 250)
    Ohio oilman, friend of John D. Rockefeller, Sr., who gave him small gifts.
    2F841
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Jennie L. Frost, 1910-1957 (Box 34, Folder 251)
    Regular John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to old-time music teacher.
    2F85
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Dr. Charles Frain, 1937-1943 (Box 35, Folder 252)
    Euclid Baptist Church member received small John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts.
    2F9
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Lucy A. Fuller, 1905-1929 (Box 35, Folder 253)
    Ohio cousin of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. received small gifts.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Edith B. Fuller, 1922-1938 (Box 35, Folder 254)
    2F91
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. J. D. Hammill, 1921-1929 (Box 35, Folder 255)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to widow of fellow church member.
    2H1
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Rev. Horace Hinsdale; Miss Katherine Hinsdale, 1905-1937 (Box 35, Folder 256)
    Regular John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to Rev. Hinsdale till his 1917 death; gift to daughter.
    2H5
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Miss Marie C. Lamberty, 1909-1932 (Box 35, Folder 257)
    Small monthly stipend to former maid.
    2I2
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. M. C Leland, 1906-1930 (Box 35, Folder 258)
    Small John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to daughter of old Cleveland friend.
    2I31
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. S. J. Life, 1906-1932 (Box 35, Folder 259)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to teacher of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s sisters.
    2I4
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. L. B. Love, 1907-1933 (Box 35, Folder 260)
    5th Avenue Baptist Church worker aided by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    2L9
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Cornelia S. Moore, 1895-1935 (Box 36, Folder 261)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to Cleveland friend.
    2M7
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Starr J. Murphy, 1937-1942 (Box 36, Folder 262)
    Large gifts to Starr J. Murphy's widow.
    2M5
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. E. B. Nightingale, 1905-1943 (Box 36, Folder 263)
    Small gifts to upstate cousin.
    2N5
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. A. B. Pulling, 1933-1959 (Box 36, Folder 264)
    Regular John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to upstate cousin who outlived both benefactors.
    2P
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Burr Pulling, 1955-1957 (Box 36, Folder 265)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $500 to aid son of Mrs. Pulling hospitalized with cancer.
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Eleanor Rockefeller, 1918-1930 (Box 36, Folder 266)
    Small gifts to Brooklyn cousins.
    2Sr
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. D. F. Roe, 1898-1937 (Box 36, Folder 267)
    Small gifts to Brooklyn cousin.
    2R72
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Rev. John Richmond, 1918-1933 (Box 36, Folder 268)
    Small John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to Ormond minister.
    2R5
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Lucy Shaver, 1899-1938 (Box 36, Folder 269)
    Gifts to Uncle Egbert Rockefeller's daughter.
    2S5
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Jennie Splain, 1895-1916; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 37, Folder 270)
    Case also involves cousins S. Van Duyne and M. A. O'Hara and Mrs. Splain's brother W. B. Davison, who received gifts.
    2S62
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Jennie Splain, 1917-1960; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 37, Folder 271)
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Hattie Treadwell, 1910-1933 (Box 37, Folder 272)
    Relation of Delap got small gifts.
    2T8
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Catherine Avery Vedder, 1929-1939 (Box 37, Folder 273)
    Brooklyn cousin got small gifts.
    2V
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Nora Walker, 1923-1936 (Box 37, Folder 274)
    Small gifts to New York cousin.
    2W1
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. W. G. Wedemeyer, 1923-1938 (Box 37, Folder 275)
    Small gifts to widow of Lakewood minister.
    2W3
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Lillian Willcox, 1915-1956 (Box 37, Folder 276)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. regular gifts to distant relative and her family; she provided John D. Rockefeller, Sr. with information regarding various cousins, etc.
    2W4
  - Donations - Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Donations and Loans - Mrs. Sarah P. Willard, 1891-1929 (Box 38, Folder 277)
    Spelman relative gave John D. Rockefeller, Jr. "Book on Tithes."
    2W5
  - Donations - Willard S. Richardson and Robert W. Gumbel Special Fund, 1927-1952 (Box 38, Folder 278)